NOAH KIMUTAI CHEPKWONY

TEL: (+254) 792133507 E MAIL: kimtaichepkwony@yahoo.com

P. O Box: 85952 – 00200 (Nairobi)

I am a self-motivated, hardworking Geospatial Information Science professional with one year of experience using Geospatial Data analysis techniques for water utilities, environment resource management and engineering construction from working at KURA, Mathira Water and Sanitation Company and NEMA. Where I worked on several projects starting from the initial planning stage, data collection, data processing, and analysis up to the output presentation stage. I am ready to apply my acquired analytical skills and personal attributes to solving problems facing society while recognizing the role of technology, teamwork, and individual contribution in providing lasting solutions. I have a positive attitude towards learning new skills.

EXPERIENCES

August 2021- To Date.

Ass. Surveyor at Kenya Urban Roads Authority (KURA).

- Setting out of construction works including pavements, earthworks, concrete works, drainage and services.
- Establishing and maintaining vertical control points.
- Managing daily tasks in a timely manner and adhering to road construction schedules.
- Undertaking site and office-based surveying works including performing calculations and reducing data.
- Data capturing, analyzing, and manipulation to produce drawings and reports.

Liaising with clients/stakeholders/onsite personnel.

June 2020-30th June 2021.

GIS Analyst intern at Mathira Water & Sanitation Company

Worked as a GIS analyst intern and conducted the following activities:

- Developed designs, layout sketches, and profiles for both water and sewerage lines.
- Created and maintained the company's geodatabase.
- Mapped water and sewerage-related utilities such as Consumers' meters, existing treatment facilities, sewerage, and water lines.
- Collaboratively worked with the non-Revenue water team and used GIS technology in the reduction of non-Revenue water.
- Generating accurate and timely reports.
- Trained colleagues on data collection and application of GIS in water service provision.
- Set up an open-source data collection tool to be used by the company (Qfield).

January 2019 - April 2019.

External attachment at The Survey of Kenya, Ruaraka.

Worked under training and education coordinator at the Survey of Kenya and gained skills in the following areas:

- Checking cadastral files for approvals and land registration.
- Field surveys to establish control points and re-establishing old ones.
- Data collection from topographic maps through digitizing.

January 2018-April 2018.

External attachment at National Environment Management Authority (NEMA).

Worked under senior GIS officer at NEMA GIS & Research department and gained skills in the following areas:

- Data collection. Downloading satellite images from open-source data sources and NEMA data receiver system and field surveys using handheld GPS.
- Data Preprocessing. i.e., data cleaning, data conversion, and re-projection.
- Data Analysis; Spatial analysis and statistical analysis.
- Project reports writing and presentation.
- Geospatial Data Analysis output presentation.

Skills.

GIS and Remote Sensing Skills.

- Coordinate system and coordinate system transformations.
- Geocoding.
- Geospatial data Analysis.
- Cartographic design and map making for variety of prints and electronic formats.
- Database design, creation, and maintenance for spatial data and non-spatial data.
- Satellite images preprocessing, data extraction and classification.
- Post classification analysis and accuracy assessment

Computer and Programming skills.

- GIS softwares (QGIS, ArcGIS and, Geomedia, AutoCAD Civil 3D)
- Python programming.
- Database Management (SQL, PostgreSQL)
- Web programming (fundamental understanding of CSS, HTML and Python)
- Microsoft office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Access).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

BSc. Geomatics & Geospatial Information Systems; (Second Class Upper Division)2020
Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent)
- Kiswahili (Fluent)
- Kalenjin (Native)

REFEREES

Caroline Susu

Prof. Charles N. Mundia

Sylvester Mahithya

Ass. Technical Manager,
MAWASCO

Kimathi University.

Tel: +254720901138

Tel: +254-729-933-154

mutyauvyu@gmail.com

ndegwa.mundia@gmail.co

<u>m</u>